All right, continue through the summer
and end a uh a quiet month of July for
the S&P. A brutal market for factors,
for tech, for the AI trades, and for
hedge funds. Um, I'll go through all of
it, try to give you uh both some
experiential perspective from having
been through uh a bunch of what
situational awareness uh went through uh
starting early in my career. So
hopefully everything I'm going through
will help to some degree. I'm going to
talk a lot about is that the end of what
went on and what to look for. I do think
there's a high probability that this was
a uh a cleansing event. uh I don't see
everything just racing back up, but I do
think that when you hit those types of
events, and I'll go through the reasons
why, uh it's probably more important
than you realize just because of what
happens when a hedge fund actually goes
under of that size. Uh number eight,
compute demand is insatiable. I just
want to make sure that
if I'm wrong about everything that you
guys watch on a weekly basis,
number eight's the most important thing
because I say it on every interview. I
say it every week here. Compute demand
is insatiable. There is no way for the
supply side to keep up with the demand
of Q compute currently and there are no
indications that that's case. But most
of the bearish rhetoric comes from the
fact that people are worried that we're
overbuilding. We're not going to get the
revenues. I'm going to cover all of that
this week based on the earnings, based
on podcasts again at a time when people
are so negative on AI from so many
different directions. And as someone who
puts their um neck out on the line
believing and using and talking about
this, the sentiment is very easy for me
to hear based on the emails I'm getting
from subscribers. Um, yes, people are
losing money. I've lost money this month
in in in a big way and I my positions
are reduced. So, I get the fact that
when uh positions go against you, it's
tough, but that's the market and that's
what goes on. Uh, I'm not here to tell
you everything is a guarantee.
Everything I do is based on
probabilities. The one thing that I do
think is an absolute guarantee is that
the market structure has changed forever
and I'm going to cover that as well. And
I think it's important particularly for
institutions
uh hedge funds, mutual funds.
Let's get into it. So this is something
that I ran. Now this was through uh
Wednesday. So this is the Goldman Sachs
H or VIP hedge fund index. So they
create an index of the most crowded
positions or the most owned positions in
the hedge fund world based on their
data. I created took that index and the
GS hedge is relative to the S&P 500.
This is a monthly look back since the
index was created which goes all the way
back to 2001.
Down 12% for the month. So that would
mean that in a month that the S&P
finishes unchanged. Now again, this is
through Wednesday. The S&P was down
about 2% through Wednesday. Um, this was
by far the worst relative performance of
that crowded hedge fund positioning,
which again, hedge funds are smart.
They're doing their homework. If it's
crowded position, that means there's got
to be good fundamentals to it. Uh,
worse than during the month of Lehman.
That's what that month is there, too.
and but but aside from that doubled any
other month. So this was a massive
shock to the hedge fund side in terms of
crowded positions. I did a rolling four
day. Seven of the 12% occurred in the
four days from Friday of last week until
Wednesday of this week. So Friday,
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday. That
four-day rate of change on that was the
worst ever. And that includes during
COVID when everything was collapsing at
the market level. Again, markets going
down. This is happening in a tape where
the S&P is not moving and the VIX is
low. This will get into the market
structure side. So, we started getting
these stories. This actually came out on
Thursday morning. Hedge funds face
demands to stump up collaterals. AL
stocks tumble. So, at this point, news
was starting to circulate that there was
a problem. So this is Thursday morning
before the market. This is in the FT. So
this is during European time. And
clearly something is happening. And then
you in the article it says Goldman
Sachs, JP Morgan were among the banks
that had asked clients to stump up
additional collateral. According to
several people familiar with the matter,
the additional collateral were
automatically triggered by market
volatility.
Goldman said in a recent note that the
buildup in gross leverage in the first
five months of the year was the largest
cumulative increase it have recorded
since it began tracking the data in
2016.
And this was already at all-time highs
according to data which I'll show you
guys later.
In a sign of the pain for hedge funds
long short hedge fund strategies were
down over 1% multistrats were down over
1.7. U basically the last time all these
strategies were down more than 1% a
single day was during COVID. However,
and this is probably the most important
line in the first thing I want you to
think about, which I did in my midweek
market update this week for subscribers,
which is hedge fund strategies were
still on average up more than 10% for
the year. Now, I don't think this was
through Wednesday. I think this is
through the Friday before. As I told
you, it was a brutal week, but then you
got the bounce back. So, figure they're
down. They're up less than 10, but
that's still up a lot. And I talk about
this often. During these situations,
chip stack matters. So when your chip
stack is still positive, you're a lot
more likely to just hedge your stuff up
and then come back to fight another day.
Now the situational awareness Leupold
[clears throat]
seeks to raise capitals after the AI
route. So again, this is in the FT
and we find out
on Thursday at 11:30ish that Citadel
buys situational awareness stock
portfolio after big losses in AI.
So there's a lot to talk about in this.
Um I just want to bring this up that
this is the kind of thing that does mark
bottoms normally. [clears throat] Do I
think there's a lot of other funds that
are possibly in a similar situation?
Yes, there probably are. The difference
is number one, this fund is very large.
And number two, as I go through this, I
want you to just pay attention. Citadel
is obviously much larger. Situational
awareness is reported to have had 45
billion worth of positions. Um, I'll go
through some of the details, but these
are the articles or two separate
articles that I just want to make sure
you hear because based on my experience,
this is the reason why I think there's a
high probability that this was a market
cleansing event. Even if there's say
another hundred hedge funds that are in
the same situation as situational
awareness, but the question is, if you
take a hundred hedge funds of a billion
dollars, you go through what they've
hedged up already, does it really matter
that much? And I'm going to say no. Um
the hedge fund is working with prime
brokers including Bank of America,
Goldman Sachs, JP Morgan to meet margin
calls or wind down positions in orderly
way. Key thing in this multiple prime
brokers know what's going on. The banks
had been marketing. It's a key word
marketing a portfolio of hedge funds
long and short holdings before the
market opened on Thursday.
I was involved in LTCM
in a very close manner both before uh in
the six months before during the
closeown I took over the S&P book when
it wasn't even completed yet. Um I've
seen this from LTCM back but I was also
very involved in the GARP quant unwind
of 2007 before the great financial
crisis and also Archos. Um there's been
other mini ones but those are the main
ones. I don't consider Melvin Capital to
be in the same side, but what you're
dealing with is once the marketing of
the portfolio begins and they start
looking for buyers.
Basically, you're showing people po
people other people's poker hands and
they're going going to go out there and
they're going to hedge their book or
front it or do whatever. In another one,
multi strategy hedge fund firm
Millennium Management also had a bid. So
when you combine Millennium and Citadel,
these firms both combine trillions of
dollars of of positions. So of course,
if they've seen what's going on and to
the extent, there's a variety of things
that are going to happen, but the
reality is this fall that we saw here,
which is really those last four days.
And the reason I have this chart up,
this is Bloom Energy relative to Adobe.
And effectively when you go through
their positions, the biggest ones they
have, the short positions that are
rumored, this is a pretty good proxy for
their book. The reason I bring this up
is they go around shopping things
because they've given back a sizable
portion. And when you give back a
sizable portion of your gains, even if
they are up 80% year to date, with half
or threequarters of that being their
private anthropic position, you're still
getting very close to the fact where you
can't meet cash because the anthropic is
not going to go through. So they have to
find someone to buy their book and give
them the cash necessary to meet the
collateral calls. So you get this
massive sell-off and then immediately at
that day you've got a change that's gone
on. You've had a cleansing event. So in
my mind given the fact that Bloom Energy
gave back everything that it had to the
point where we got the last 13F
holdings, which is right here, which is
where we saw situational awareness's
positions. I do think that you have to
start from the perspective of is the
unwind over.
It's definitely not over from people
that need to get out. They never are.
But the question is, are there more
people in a position now that have
already hedged their portfolio?
Especially when you're dealing with the
prime brokers and the largest banks out
there who have been the banks were
already out there asking for more
collateral. And then you have the two
biggest hedge funds or two of the
biggest hedge funds in the world also
seeing the situation and having
positions on internally as well. So I
did this during the week and I just want
to bring this up. This was an especially
important risk management week with the
Federal Reserve major hyperscaler
earnings and the end of a brutal month
for momentum. That's what made this
situation worse. And honestly, this is
what obviously took Leupold over the
edge is that going into the week from
last Friday when there was clearly a
problem. You had a big week coming up
where the Fed and I'm not a tinfoil
person, but the fact that Citadel came
out with a news story saying surprise
rate hike uh was their call for Kevin
Worsh. and you have the hyperscaler
earnings which could cut capex and that
rumor was flying around and you've
already had a brutal month which means
people are playing with a short a short
stack. That's why I went through this to
kind of go through midweek. So for those
of you who are subscribers I've done a
midweek I think every week this week in
July or at least the last three weeks.
Um and the reason is because there was a
lot going on in this but also a lot
going on in the thematic portfolio which
uh I've obviously put on the the
website. It's part of this because it's
correlated to everything that's gone on.
So this was the Citadel security seeing
Worsh delivering surprise rate hike. So
when you put it all together, you're
back with I saw LTCM.
I saw the Quan unwind in 2007. Was
involved in it. Had positions on in both
of those by Archos. I was not involved
in it other than having a variety of 30
some odd portfolio managers reporting to
me and all of them end up in the same
situation where you get the point and
then margin calls from several global
investment banks. They all know what's
going on. Block trade started to happen
in this case. It's a little bit of all
of them to me. I had said before that
the market movements were reminding me
more of LTCM than anything and the quant
unwind as well. LTCM is different in the
fact that that leverage was impacting
the world and all of the markets around
the globe except for the US markets were
already falling in this case almost all
the markets around the world are above
their 200 day moving average and
continuing to move higher. So, one of
the elements that came on again last
week that was an indication is someone
and it was either Leopold or preparing
for while they're going out to go out
and figure out how to market this. There
were multiple billion dollars of SMH
puts that were bought
uh to hedge things. So, SMH falls
violently in the four days and guess
what? You have this massive volume spike
basically on the lows. Um
I I you know for everyone who's looking
for things in here and again this is
actually an awesome looking chart for
the size of the unwind that's happened.
I said this before this is an ABC at
this point. Um the lows to me are
critical and I'll go through that as
well. Uh but I mentioned Micron last
week. There's a neckline of a head and
shoulders formation right here that we
broke below and that we've broken back
above. Now, at this point, this was the
most interesting part. Uh the day before
the news articles came out, uh this was
the second day in a row that uh people
had called me up saying that someone was
being unwound and something big was
happening. So, this is the day after
Kevin Worsh. So, this is Wednesday. The
market sold off. The S&P was down 120
points, which it made all back the day,
the next day. This was clearly the day
that the positions were taken on hold by
I'm assuming Citadel and they take these
positions on and then there's a massive
futures position that goes on and the
reason that you can see this is this is
the total year-to- date volume of the E-
Minis the S&P electronic futures from
2:00 to 4:00 so into the close except
for one day which was June 4th which
happened to be the gap down here which
was a big volume day. This was the
biggest volume for E- mini futures in
that 2hour period into the close of the
entire year. So that's how you know that
a lot of the selling was done in a
pukage basis by just hedging what had
gone on. So when someone comes to the
market and let's assume that the reports
are correct and he sold about 15 to 20
billion dollars of positions at the
market bid down a certain amount. Well,
the futures, it's not surprising they
get knocked down one one and change
percent. Uh, they probably bought
everything down as an index 3% down, 4%
down, 5% down. So, I used to do this
when I traded the S&P book. Um, these
types of things go on and you make
markets on them and that's what happens
and I think that's what went on. Now, it
doesn't get past the fact that as of
Thursday morning
before we got the bounce, this is where
the momentum factor was for technology.
Down 40% year to date.
Worse than anything during the dotcom
bubble by almost 20% except for this one
period here I that one month there. So
again, historic month for industrial
momentum
again before the market opened on
Thursday, down 32%. I mean double any
other month.
This one's the most important,
especially for you multistrats, but also
for um anyone who's factor uh focused.
If you strip out the factor risk of your
portfolio, then you're running a factor
neutral portfolio that's also going to
be sector neutral. This is sector
neutralized momentum
as of again Thursday morning down 21%.
Um now again when you look at the months
that were up these were unprecedented up
months. This is an unprecedented down
month. So again we're giving back gains
and this is the way it goes. You stretch
the rubber band too far one way you get
levered. This is the reason why I did
the AI midcycle slowdown because we had
stretched the rubber band too much one
way. I got crap for getting out of
Micron way too early and then I got crap
last week for saying I was buying Micron
below 900.
Guys, I'm going to go through this as it
goes on. When you see these types of
moves, if you think you're going to be
able to pick tops and bottoms, I've
never in my lifetime be able to pick
tops and bottoms. What I'm trying to do
is increase positions based on a basian
philosophy of the news that's coming for
me. If you're watching this to try and t
pick tops and bottoms, especially in the
speed chess world, it's not going to
happen. This down here is already
extended. It was extended down here. It
was extended here. You're trying to stay
solvent by waiting until the panic
subsides. And we saw a panic situation
that historically signals the end. In
terms of those four days, this is more
shocking. This is the 4-day rate of
change again into the close on Wednesday
for
sector neutralized momentum. So again,
this is a long short basket down 17%
that is sector neutral. So this is
momentum across all sectors. It just
shows the extent of the damage. Now I've
talked about this before and this is why
everything has changed going forward.
Um, this is as of uh the close on
Friday.
This is the current 30-day and 60-day
realized V of the Morgan Stanley tech
momentum factor. There is no way that
this doesn't keep the risk at lower
levels. So, even if people have
derisked, they're not going to re-risk
anywhere near where they were before.
[clears throat] Partly because of the
draw down, partly because some of them
are going to be in the hole. But a lot
of it has to do with until this
volatility comes down and I don't expect
it to come down quickly and I still
believe structurally it's going to be
higher than it's been in the past. This
is the main problem. This is something
which is beyond belief to be up at 110
when the prior highs were around 70
which means a normal move right now in
the market taking the square root of 252
108 divided around divided by the square
root of 252 which is 16 gives you about
6 to 7% a day and that's market or you
know that's that's market neutral in the
fact it's dollar long dollar short these
types of moves are huge. Now, if you
take it a step further, what I did is I
took all of the market neutralized
factors. So, forget just the tech
momentum side, which is tech, and I took
it for beta, I took it for quality, I
took it for momentum, and I took it for
value. And I just went through and gave
it an equal weight. So, divide each of
them by four. They're uh 60-day
volatility. And here's where we are. 38.
We're above. So this gets into any kind
of optimized portfolio where you're risk
weighting even your factors.
Th this is something that has been
trending higher for some time. Just
look, you don't see anything where this
stuff trends higher for a long period of
time. This is the impact of AI and it is
never going away. And I'm going to go
through the reasons why. We Here's more
um on the liquidations that went on and
just some more of the stats. Hedge funds
just sold more tech than any point in
Goldman's 10-year record. momentum
factor volatility at its highest in 45
years outside a recession. So I don't
even have data going back 45 years.
Gross and net exposure is off five and
four-year highs now in the middle of the
pack. Six weeks of that and hedge funds
are still up 9% through June. Again
through June, one of the best first
halves in 20 years. So again, that was
through June. So I'm going to remind you
guys, I wrote this paper back in May.
Bubbles, parabas, and speed crashes.
This is exactly what we saw. So I wrote
this before the peak. We're going to see
more bubbles. We're going to see more
par parabas. And what comes with that
are speed crashes. So it's going to look
like a bubble. Basically, we're
compressing time. And the reason we're
compressing time is because AI is
compressing time. The model capabilities
are going so fast and we're entering
into a world of AI agents which are on
24/7. It's the end of human beings. Now,
this has been happening anyway. If you
guys have been down in the New York
Stock Exchange anytime
uh since the 1990s, it looks a lot
different today than it did back then.
We've already been in this situation.
Machine learning has already been a part
of our world. It's just that now it is
ubiquitous and everyone has it. You have
to incorporate that into what's going on
now. We not only saw the liquidations
for hedge funds in Korea, we've
basically been in a 3-w week unwind of
positions there. So again, we've
cleansed positions, but you're not going
to be able to take that kind of size
again. So don't expect this to go back
to the same direction because what
chased it, as someone who focuses a lot
on Bitcoin and on uh crypto, you need
the energy of retail, and we're just not
going to get back to that anytime soon.
I talked about that with silver, gold,
and Bitcoin. The difference is with the
AI trades, for those of you, I say it
every week, the majority of positions
are above the 200 day moving average
still. So of the AI positions, I think
74% are still above and 84% of my basket
are still the 200 day moving average is
still going higher. So we're not in any
position where any damage was done.
Hedge fund leverage,
this was as of the third quarter of 2025
and this is data from the Securities and
Exchange Commissions form PF.
You can see how much it had gone up
since co hedge funds had been having
performance.
this has gone higher. It's not just the
basis trade. It is also equities. So,
this is not just fixed income. It is
across a range of places. Now, I want to
bring this up because I wrote this paper
on the art of unlearning the Fed, which
we'll get back to, but I just want to
read this line because this is what goes
for everyone who's a risk manager. If
you're out of fun and your risk manager
doesn't watch my videos, I would give
them this because this is a structural
change. AI is progressing at an
unprecedented pace and in a world
defined by exponential innovation,
relying on backward-looking models is
too slow. This was me writing about what
Scott Besson had said in an interview on
the All-In Pod when he was going through
what was going to have to happen with
the Fed. Here's the way that it's doing
it. First of all, AI is compressing
economic time. The model capabilities
are improving rapidly. So, what used to
take 10 years in innovation is now
taking a year. We went through this in
the first quarter. Terminal value harder
to estimate. You don't know if you're
going to be in business in three years
if you're built on code. Think Adobe.
Think Salesforce. People still have no
idea. So there was multiple compression
because we were taking off terminal
value. All this feeds into the factors.
If all of a sudden we don't know if a
company is going to go, they can go down
40% without their earnings changing.
This is not good for risk management in
terms of having this instability. Hedge
funds operate on a much shorter clock
than the assets they own. This is going
to be a big deal, especially as we get
into tokenization where things are going
to trade 24 hours a day. Are the hedge
funds going to be in a position to trade
this stuff 24 hours a day? How much more
miserable is life going to get if you're
down big over the weekend? The more that
markets are open or trading, the more
likely you are to make an emotional
response that is bad. Leverage turns
valuation uncertainty into liquidity
risk.
That is important because when you get
falling confidence in terminal value, it
raises volatility, tightens financial
conditions. We're seeing all of these
play out. So, I don't think the prime
brokers are going to allow leverage to
go to the levels they have because I
don't think the volatility that we saw
is coming down. Ubiquitous AI risk tools
create a false sense of confidence. This
is like watching people drive down the
street with all-wheel drive when it's
icy and snowy out, thinking that they're
protected. Everyone right now has AI
risk tools. You can just say optimize
this portfolio. What is a way to reduce
my risk,
you're just at a point where there's a
bubble in optimization and thinking that
your portfolio is hedged because it's
using, as Scott Bessant alluded to, the
way that you come up with an optimized
portfolio is that you're using past
correlations and past volatility. As
I've shown you in the factor stuff, this
is no longer relevant unless you believe
mean reversions happening. And I'm
telling you, the market structure has
changed forever because of AI. It is
never going back. Tokenization is here.
Terminal value is gone forever. All of
this stuff is happening. You're seeing
things like companies that are private
like Anthropic grow so fast, the fastest
in the history of companies, but also
seeing companies go out of business
faster than they've ever. The greater
terminal value uncertainty leads to
multiple compression. That's what we're
seeing. So, the S&P 500 earnings are
growing at over 20% a year, but the
multiples compressing because the stocks
are not going up to match it. If you
don't believe the AI agents are here,
Robin Hood keeps releasing things.
Here's an AI trading agent now reads
charts, RSI, MACD, and 16 more. This
means retail has access to the same
tools that every quant hedge fund has.
Now, we're going to get through the
changes that are happening and how
disastrous this is, especially for the
month of July because I am sure there
are lots of people. I get so many people
that reach out saying they've been
buying S&P puts, they've been buying
NASDAQ puts, this is going to crash. I'm
not kidding you when I say that very
smart people who I respect keep
constantly calling up with this stuff.
Here's what's gone on. This is tech
momentum. the one-year realized V at 67
and a half. Here is the NDX realized V
for the same time period. Here is the
relationship over time.
This is insanity.
You're at one of the lowest levels of
realized volume in the NDX and you are
parabolic on the volatility.
This is where RAAS, mutual funds,
everyone who doesn't have the same time
horizon as a hedge fund
should be having a conversation with me.
We're getting those conversations. This
is about market structure. You can
benefit significantly from this. And
from the people that I talked to
regularly, they did very well reducing
risk back in May, even though it was
early, because they're in a position
right now to start building up some of
the risk on fundamentals that they like.
There's going to be more speed crashes,
guys, than there ever have been. If you
don't believe that chart, here is that
factor neutral V that I said, which is
at 36, which again takes an equal weight
of quality beta momentum and value
sector neutral factors equal weight
relative to the six contract of the VIX.
So for everyone who's bought S&P vault
or sixmonth, this thing tends to go
higher and we could be in an event right
now where multiple hedge funds are going
under. If you ask me as I'll get
through, the only two areas when I've
spoken to the risk group at the Fed that
I'm worried about, I'm worried about
insurance companies and I'm worried
about hedge funds. Those are the only
groups that I think have the leverage
capable of this going up here. That
would be a credit event. I think that
needs to involve either a hedge funds,
but since Citadel Millennium are up big
for the year and they're involved in
this stuff and they're the best risk
managers in the world, we're probably in
a situation where this is more likely to
decompress over time. And that's my
baseline. If you ask me what's more
likely to happen, I don't think there's
going to be a major event. I think
there's going to be multiple compression
and I think there's going to be a lot of
disappointment, but I think deleveraging
is going to happen for a long time
because of this staying up here. So, if
you ask my gut, I don't think we're mean
reverting anymore. We've already seen a
structural higher level here than it was
all back here. And this is not a short
time period. This basically stayed
between five and 15 from 2000 to 2020.
Since then, it's been from 15 to 30.
We're in a structurally higher
volatility, so you're just going to have
to deal with it. Here's another one.
This is taking the VIX which is the
index implied V and this is taking the
VIX EQ which is the equity
V. So equity V has broken away. This is
the longterm relationship between the
two and we've got a huge difference here
and effectively it started right around
Chat GPT. So, I just think that equity
vault because you can go out of business
much very quickly is going to stay at
the high side and index vault is going
to stay on the lower side relative to
it. Um, again, if you want to reach out,
especially if you're an RAIA where I'm
having these conversations, you can do
it weekly, you can do it monthly, but I
think being on top of the factor side,
being on top of the AI from a bigger
perspective, asking the questions,
that's where the alpha is going to be
generated. So, you can reach out on
there. Um,
this is a bull market still. 67 new
highs in the S&P yesterday, the most
since February. So, as this whole thing
has been going on in July, we've got
that. We got 72% of the S&P 500, greater
than our 50-day, 200 day, 68% above the
20-day. I mean, again,
everything's been fine during this.
Here's where we finished the month,
unchanged.
four sectors down,
seven up.
This is not normal compared to what went
on in LTCM and what went on during the
quant unwind. It is similar to Archos.
Argos ended up going higher from there.
But I think you just have to pay
attention. Here's a chart on the S&P and
remember that was the day where we sold
off at the end of the day and we've
immediately not only gone back up. The
next day we went higher and now we
closed way above it. I'm going to get
into some of the technicals on that, but
just be aware that every time we kind of
push this ball underneath the water, it
pops out. Here's equal weight S&P, the
monthly returns.
Look at how many months we've been up
with only one month down, which was when
the invasion or the bombing of of Iran
occurred and oil spiked higher.
This is a broad market in terms of the
rally that's going on. Here's the NDX.
So we hit the lowest RSI in the last
year. You look at what happened the last
time we got down to this level and we
had a similar type day where we were
down and the next day we gapped higher
down gapped higher. We'll see what
happens. Uh I'm going to go through some
of the technicals but remember this is
very correlated with my thematic
portfolio. the AI trade in general,
semiconductors, the NDX did go down and
NDX over the S&P actually had its worst
month since the.com bubble. Believe it
or not, guys, uh worst month since
the.com bubble.
Here's SMH. As I mentioned, we had this
reverse head and shoulders. I'm telling
you, um, again, these lows need to hold,
but reverse head and shoulders where you
break the neckline, everyone gets short.
I'm sure a lot of people got short here,
and then we gap higher and then we sit
there. Technically,
this is what I'd be focused on. If you
guys aren't, you know, uh, aware of
follow-through days,
a follow-through day is confirmation
that an oversold bounce may be turning
into a real investable rally rather than
just a short covering pop. So, the
reason I like this and the reason I used
it, made a lot of money off this after
bottoms. Um, I preferred to find bottoms
than tops because generally the
sentiments there, you get these very
noticeable signals. I was talking about
all the things that bothered me
beginning in May and the market kept
going higher. Situational awareness
going out of business and all the things
that I showed you in the beginning of
this that is very indicative of a
cleansing event. Typically technicians
look for it a few days after the low
often four day uh day four through 10 of
an of rally attempt. A major index rises
meaningfully. It's common volume is
higher blah blah blah. So basically what
you're looking for is give it time.
Here's the low. The next day we have the
biggest volume since June. This is on
the cues. So we get this selloff here.
This is the day again that we get the
panic from Liupold. So the positions
trade war speaks. We get this massive
selloff. The next day we trade on higher
volume. We close above the highs of that
day. Structurally a good thing. Do I
think we're probably going to spend time
here? They're talking about day four to
10. So, as we move out here, if we hold
the lows and if we just kind of build
this time in here, that's a good sign.
That's what I'm looking for. Um, we'll
see what happens. If you're looking for
fundamentals to support this,
uh, we're now through 60% of the S&P.
Uh, sales growth since earnings growth
is a little bit, not a little, it's a
lot distorted by, uh, anthropic inside
this. But when you go through each of
these, just look how big these numbers
are. It's every sector. More
importantly,
sales growth 14%. I mean, guys, I keep
saying it. It's like it doesn't pay to
be to be bearish stocks when this is
going on. You have so much fundamental
support and revisions as we go through
earning season again going higher. So,
not only are they beating numbers, not
only are they coming through on a
historical basis, the revisions keep
moving higher. You don't want to be
bearish on stocks while this is going
on. This is the longest period now in
the last five years. It's very
difficult. So, we'll see what happens.
Here's my thematic portfolio. So, last
week we were over here. I said we're at
the 50. It wouldn't surprise me to see
us go lower. Blah blah blah. We did.
We're back up in here. We're in the 30
some odd. Is that it? I'm like I said,
I'm betting on the fact right now with
my own portfolio off the lows of that
panic low that that was it. If not,
there's something bigger going on. Hedge
funds could be massively unwinding.
We'll see what happens. But that's why
we trade these lows. We don't sit there
and invest them. Um, I have positions on
and things I believe in, which I'll
have. And then the positions like Micron
and AA ai and uh Marll and some of the
other things I've added to. We'll just
see where everything goes. Here's a
thematic portfolio on an RSI basis.
14-day RSI hit the same level it did
here on the lows here again.
We'll see what goes on. But as of right
now, I'm leaning towards that. Now, this
is the thing that I want you guys to
understand in terms of adding. Go back
to what I said, how factors are changing
and market structures changing. Never
before, in my opinion, has looking at
the rate of change been more important.
Most people I know don't use this. I've
always used it since my days in Brazil.
Uh I do believe markets move on a rate
of change basis and it pays to reduce
risk when you get above historic levels.
Now in May and into here is when I was
reducing my micron position. So
beginning around the middle of May a
little bit all the time a little bit of
Marll until we got up here. Now this is
the 63day rate of change. So this is 63
trading days which is three months. We
made it all the way up to we were up
over 50% on a look back of the prior 63
days for the thematic portfolio.
Now over the last 63 days, we're down
1.7%. We have now retraced. We have now
done what we needed to do in both price
and time. And that's what it takes with
rate of change. When I did the
consolidation and I showed you the the
consolidation patterns that are likely
to happen, it's time and price. So we've
done that. So, this is just a metric for
you guys to use. I provide it every
single week in that technical sheet and
I'll show you some of the things in
there on the 30-day basis. So, a month
and a half or a month and a quarter down
15%. So, from as my father taught me,
the odds on the AI trade are much better
than they were at here. This is on a
30-day basis when I started to reduce
micron. So, again, you're at a much
better entry point in price and time.
I'm not trying to pick the bottoms in
this. There's a lot of new news that
went on. Now, for those of you looking
to trade the index, which I highly
recommend, if you're going to pick
names, then trade the names. But if
you're going to jump into things, the 10
name concentrated position, I just want
to make sure you guys see that it was
correlated before. I spent a lot of time
to come up with 10 names that are highly
correlated to the 100 name index. So,
you didn't have to do that. It stayed
correlated with it and traded extremely
well with it. One of the names in there
is Corning. I highlighted this this week
on the subscriber video. The thing about
corning, it hit the 200 day, it traded
up. The reason I have this chart here
from December 31st. This day here is
when the announcement came from Meta for
$6 billion.
They had another day here where Nvidia
partnered with them. So they do announce
a partnership with Nvidia. They
announced a partnership with Meta for $6
billion, which according to every LLM
that I use is equivalent to somewhere
around a hundred million dollar 100
million homes worth of fiber, optical
fiber.
And the stock got all the way back to
where it was basically on the close of
that day. This is one of the
concentrated names. Now, if you look at
it on a rate uh well, I guess I didn't
put it in there. I thought I had a rate
of change basis on it. Here are the uh
percentage names. So again, I've shown
you guys this each week. When you upload
the technical sheet, I highly recommend
going into co-work and using this to
look for this. The reason I highlighted
these is July 14th, we had 26% of the
names above the 20-day. Here we are now.
We've had two weeks where even with all
the carnage, it's starting to show signs
here of positivity relative to these two
weeks. I'm more interested in this one.
This is somewhat similar to here. If we
start to see this thing move higher
again, I think that's a good sign. 84 of
the names out of the hundred 200 day
slope rising. So, you're looking for
signs on that. I'm uploading this to the
website. This is combing through the
rubble. So, I went through and I
basically wanted to do something and
again part of this is to teach you guys
how to do this. Um, I highly recommend,
again, I do this presentation for RAAS
as well in terms of how they can go
through in someone's portfolio and be
able to show the things that are
technically still moving well and be
able to do this. So, this is two
conditions. I want to make sure that if
I'm going through the rubble, number
one, I want the uh price above the 200
day moving average. Think Micron, the
200 day moving average is somewhere 500.
We're still around 850. And I want the
200 day itself still rising. Those are
the names that structurally to me I want
to be involved in. That's my favorite
technical sign. So I want to find things
that have fallen back. And what I do in
here is I go through and rank all of
them on that. You guys will see the
list. It has all the names in it. And so
just to give you like a quick side like
I mentioned AOI, I ended up buying some
this week. And again when I say I bought
some, these are all small positions. If
you go back to what I had in May, my
micron position right now is about 1/5if
of the size that it was in May when I
was getting out of it. So again, I'm not
trying to pick the bottom of this. I'm
trying to work into something where I
don't think the upside is a good at 800.
Do I think it can get to 1,600 over the
next year? Yes. At 500, it's a better
riskreward. So I'm not convinced yet
that we've made the absolute low, but I
want to start buying some because I
think we're eventually going back up to
1500 to600. Now, in the case of this
where the slope is up on the 200 day and
the percent above the 200 day is here
and we're now 31% down for the month,
27% down over the 3 months verse the
50-day it's below by 34. Like I'm trying
to find names that are still above here,
still positive here, but are way below
in these things. So, I go through the
list. I also go through what they've
said on their earnings as well to see if
the fundamentals still line up. Here are
the two things that I want you guys to
start paying more attention to that I
have one eye open. So, I'm always as a
risk manager looking for something that
could
change my mind as to what's going on.
So, the hyperscaler CDS does not bother
me one bit. What does worry me is that
the triple C market, the option adjusted
spread has this bad looking role to it
and this is overlaid with high yield or
the junk market. So whenever I see these
divergences, the way credit usually goes
is the weak start going up and it
eventually drags everything in. There is
no doubt right now that the amount of
capital that's being absorbed by AI is
massive and I do believe the disruption
happening from AI is real. So, I think
we're going to see more and more private
credit issues. The question is, is this
some of the private credit issues that
have been in play really this entire
year? Because this started right around
the time that the software stuff fell.
So, I wouldn't ignore it. And if you
guys want to read, I I'm I love good
conspiracy theory when it comes to
credit. I like to stay on top of things
because I do believe that they start
with oneoff things and the Dodgers have
bothered me as a sports fan spending
money in any possible way. And so this
whole thing with the Dodgers,
Guggenheim,
Mark Walter, and private credit, I'm
just I would go read this and just pay
attention. I don't know what it means. I
just know the insurance industry fairly
well and I think there's a lot of
mispriced assets in there. Uh Google, I
was shocked how many people when I did
my video last week told me I was wrong
on Google. This was going to collapse.
And of course, this was here.
Sorry, here we closed below the 200 day.
Um I put this in last week. I am shocked
how many people don't care about the
backlog of Google and tell me it doesn't
mean anything. It's not real. I I
couldn't disagree more, guys. Uh I'm
going to go through a bunch of things on
this. I think you guys need to stop
reading some of the people who are
basically just doing the math like I
showed last week and saying these
earnings sucked. Clearly, Google's
earnings didn't suck. They've already
gone back up. I expect fully this
company to completely take off and keep
going because the numbers are insane in
terms of the backlog. And if you didn't
believe them, Zuckerberg comments about
compute demand from his call. There's
just nowhere near enough compute for all
the demand. We are getting a large
number of offers for the compute that we
have. Meta is not building compute ahead
of uncertain demand. Zuckerberg said
demand already exists. Available compute
blah blah blah. You don't believe them
because there's stock tradeoff.
Sundar Pachai, we continue to be supply
constrained. A sign of momentum and
rapid adoption. The demand still
outpaces the investment. Meta, there's
nowhere there's just nowhere near enough
compute for all the demand. Microsoft,
which traded much higher, customer
demand continues to exceed available
capacity. That additional inquarter
capacity for Azure was quickly
monetized. Can't tell you how many smart
people told me that these guys were
going to cut capex this quarter.
wrong.
Every incremental unit of compute
brought online is being absorbed almost
immediately while demand continues to
outrun supply. If you don't like those
hyperscalers, how about we go to Amazon?
Even at that amount, we will still not
have enough capacity to meet all of the
demand we have in 2026.
I believe this dynamic will also be true
in 2027, too. Guys, don't be short these
things. Honestly, like what are you
doing? I I don't like
the demand was already we already have
for 2028 is striking.
This may be the strongest
forward-looking comment from the call
because Amazon is already seeing
substantial commitment several years
ahead. The lion share of AWS 2027
compute capacity is already reserved. We
have a clear sign of light to strong
financial returns.
Amazon also explained why free cash flow
looks weak before the revenue arrives.
It begins spending on data. So again, I
want you to go back to what I said about
the factor risk. The model capabilities
are insane. They are moving faster and
faster. This whole open- source thing is
stupid. Yes, it will be a part of it.
Open router will go through it, but they
need to have the cloud and they need to
have these companies because they're the
only ones with the compute. Nobody else
is building the compute. I showed you
guys last week that those Chinese
companies are so tiny and they're
building compute. They have to be run
somewhere. So where do you get the
chance to use the compute of these
Chinese models? It'll have to be because
it's on bedrock or it's on wherever you
want, but it has to be on somewhere
where there's compute. Somewhere around
the line, there has to be hardware that
has the compute. There isn't any
compute.
Here are the new backlog numbers. 500
billion for Amazon, 500 billion for
Google, 700 billion. This is $1.7
trillion between those three of a
backlog. Our backlog stands at 496,
growing triple digits year-over-year. A
large amount of it tends to be deals and
agreements that you've signed. They
talked about the fact that their new
demand is not from OpenAI and Anthropic.
The majority of backlog is related to
typical GCP contracts for a broad mix of
customers.
Oh, sorry. This is the one. All
sequential commercial RPO growth was
driven by commitments from customers
outside of frontier model companies. Um,
if the people that have scared you are
not writing about the facts in the
earnings, then what they're saying is
not facts. What they're saying is trying
to use bear porn on you. You have to at
least go through. You can say that these
guys know nothing of what they're
talking about. that the Mag Seven that
are the proven track record winners that
their revenue is growing rapidly. They
are the ones spending the capex and
you're telling me the people writing
these garbage newsletters are saying
that Google, Amazon, and that they're
stupid. There is a risk that it's
circular and the fact that anthropic and
open AI go out of business, but we'll
hit on that next. Allin podcast. I
thought it was a very, very good one.
And I give these guys a lot of crap
because I think the thing has become way
too political, but lately they're back
on their uh their game. A lot of good
things in there. I'm not going to go
read all of it. Um but they go through
the Kimmy K3. They go through this. I
thought David Saxs in particular had a
ton of useful information on this just
because he's connected to the White
House and I think he was just very open
and honest about all of this stuff. He
pushes back against the panic and
basically talks about how as much as he
hates Anthropic.
He talked about how they're the fastest
growing tech company in history and that
so far their annualized revenue is at 74
billion through the halfway mark of the
year. So he's saying they're going to
grow 10 times again this year over a
hundred billion. And he mentions that
OpenAI is now on pace for about 75
billion this year. Guys, that's 175
billion in revenues from two companies
that had zero two years ago.
How can you be arguing about ROIC when
these guys are printing money at that
side and the cloud revenue guys are
printing $2 trillion during the exact
same period? So how people are coming up
with this when the companies are getting
the demand from the API side and from
enterprises at the same time that the
com cloud guys are getting it. So it's
just misleading completely. So compute
demand versus supply. Sachs goes through
it. As far as I'm concerned
there is an unlimited appetite for
ondemand intelligence. I don't think
there's an upper bound for how much
intelligence you can tap as long as it
continues to get better. I completely
agree. He goes through the numbers there
on both these things.
You have you still have stuff in the
labs by Anthropic and OpenAI that is way
ahead of the Chinese open source models.
Sam is going to Washington over the next
week to talk about GPT 6.0 which is
blowing the doors off. Again, the models
that are out, these guys have better. If
you haven't seen Sam Alman on Invest
Like the Best, I highly recommend going
through it. I thought it was one of his
better performances.
Alman says, "OpenAI's conviction to
secure massive compute came from seeing
an exponential model improvement curve,
especially around GPT4.
Basically, again, demand would be
basically uncapped."
He says the biggest near-term compute
gains may come from software efficiency.
Uh talks about the cyber incident that
happened uh with hugging space.
Uh I'll leave AGI alone and go through
it. I summarize this in a little better
ways if you guys care about, but um
the fear flip because demand exploded.
This is the thing I want to make sure.
As of
October of last year, the probability of
these companies being in trouble to me
was much much higher than at any time
during this year. And the reason was
because the the risk was these guys were
spending money and the enterprises were
never going to adopt it. that human
beings were just going to be too slow.
The only thing that changed it was that
the AI agents came on much faster. And
that's the point that a reason I did the
portfolio is because the agentic world
started and I started putting all these
names together way before it went
because I had already done the homework.
The inference demands were going to be
insatiable once AI agents reached. We
just didn't know what was going to
happen. And it happened at least a year
faster. That was how Leopold invested in
all these things as well. It just got to
that point. What Sam does say is supply
is the bottleneck today. Compute
bottleneck. The bottleneck has moved
over time. He talks about research being
a huge one. The amount of demand is just
going to accelerate. Personal agents
would massively increase demand. This is
the meta side. This is why Meta isn't
selling their compute. They could have
made investors very happy this week by
saying, "We're going to rent out our
compute," which they kind of leaked and
then they didn't do it. Why didn't they
do it? Because if they do it, personal
agents are going to massively increase
demand. So, I'm sure they've run into
this thinking this is coming faster than
what we all know and I believe that the
over supply scenario would be models
become so smart and efficient that they
can do almost anything people need with
current compute. Alman believes compute
demand is structurally under supply
because model quality unlocks new use
cases. So basically the Jevans paradox
thing gets in. Is there a chance? So
what is the most likely scenario for
supply to catch up demand based on his
views? Software agents squeeze more
intelligence out of compute. So this is
the efficiency side. Physical world
robotics so humanoids eventually expands
the entire compute supply chain. Neither
of these is happening in the next year.
It's just not happening. It it it can't
we're not there yet to be able to go
through it. And even if we are, the
demand side is going to pick up the pace
because of the personal agents. That's
why I shown you guys the chart of what
it means to have personal agents. So
agents make compute production
dramatically more efficient. Models
become so efficient that each task needs
less compute. Human attention becomes
the bottleneck. So good one to go
through. Uh I talked about the revenues.
They've seen a major uptick since May.
This is the other reason why you have to
be positive on these things. Now this
makes sense to me and I hate to say it.
Where would you expect these to be?
These guys are raising so much money. If
credit spreads weren't widening and they
weren't building in more risk as all of
these guys are spending. Of course,
there's a risk that any one of them
could go out of business if they don't
get the revenues in the door. Meta is
making a huge bet. They don't have
anything now. If they don't actually
figure this out, they'll be in trouble.
Gavin Baker market is overreacting to
hyperscaler credit spreads widening. The
fact that spot prices for GPU rentals
are at least two times higher than
contractor rates is a missing piece. I
could read all of this stuff. The
reality is at 60
billion per gigawatt that's 1.5 to 2.2
trillion in capex consensus estimates
for hyperscaler cash flow 1.3. He's just
doing the same point I am which is
we don't have enough compute right now
guys.
Darkh put this out. It I think had over
a million views um in terms of X going
through it. I highly recommend going
through to read it. It's a it's a very
contrarian thought. Uh and it really
says without going through it in a big
way, the part that matters the most.
His argument is that expensive compute
converts token efficiency into pricing
power, widens the frontier premium. So
this gets back to the fact that if these
guys continue to move at this pace and
their intelligent is better but more
importantly their token efficiency which
comes from the amount of compute they've
built. So the moat becomes the compute
that they have access to the fact that
they can charge again a reasonable price
for token efficiency. So to get this to
a point where people can understand what
it means I had to kind of go through it.
Um, and again, Gavin spoke out about
this, too.
I wanted to give you guys an analogy
that could work. Gas and cars. Why the
best AI model wins when compute gets
expensive?
If gas is a dollar a gallon, nobody
cares about the fuel efficiency.
When it's $10, everyone pays a premium
for the car with the best mileage. This
is what's going to end up happening is
that you might be able to pay cheaper
for Kimmy K 3.0, No, but it's not as
efficient as the best models. And that
situation gets worse and worse because
you need more hardware or compute. And
if there isn't any hardware or compute
to run it, the only place that has it is
the place with the compute.
If Anthropic has
an enormous amount of token efficiency
and Disney wants to take a $5 billion
movie cost but make it for hund00
million, that margin of being able to
buy all of the compute that Anthropic
has, not only gives them an insane way
to make tons of money, but it gets them
to destroy their competition as well.
So, we're getting to the point where you
have to look at the token efficiency.
This is the other reason why I've
written so much about Vera Rubin. We're
getting into a situation where token
efficiency is the story, not token
maxing. And just remember how much
SpaceX was able to do for their compute.
So we have a shortage of compute. The
models are going faster. They're
bringing on more demand because they're
getting better and better, but there
isn't enough compute out there. So the
people that have already built the
compute, those prices are going to get
higher and higher as SpaceX saw, as Meta
saw when they realized that they could
sell this stuff out. So just keep it in
the back of your mind that we're
reaching a point where it's great that
there's all these competitive models,
but you have to be able to run them on
something. And the question is where is
that compute going to come from? And if
the models are more efficient in terms
of the token usage, you're still going
to go back to using a a better model
except for the stuff that's free that
you download on there. So we're not at a
point yet where we have the hardware for
everyone to be running open source
models. So there's at least another two
years in my opinion and that's more than
enough time based on what we heard from
the hyperscalers this week as to when
they're going to get the revenue in the
door. It's not a given. I gave you guys
a probability last week but it is
happening. Now if you still don't
believe that the data centers and the
compute then just look at DRAM prices.
This is the weekly prices of DRAM and
again this is the oldest one. This goes
back to 2016. This is not the newest
memory.
They're still going up every week. So,
the cyclicality, cyclicality, green,
mainly red. Look how many weeks this is
going on and it's not stopping. Yes,
it's slowing down because the price has
gone up so high. All right, let's bang
through the the rest of these. Uh, I did
want to do something on the Fed because
again, so many people talking about it
this week. People telling me some of
these strategists were saying it could
be 50. So, he holds rates three. The Fed
did exactly what Wall Street was
expecting. So why are the markets so
vexed by Kevin Worsh again? The art of
unlearning the Fed. If you didn't read
it, go read it. This is the world that I
think we're in. Again, I think Kevin
Worsh is a smart guy. I think he has
talked publicly about the fact that we
can't be using the academic approach of
the past. We got to have a task force in
to figure out the new things to use. The
data that we're using now is not only
stuff that gets revised. It's old. We
need to be more forwardlooking. The Fed
is not the same Fed and this whole
dovish hawkish thing is not there. Now
tenure rates are sitting up near 470.
Here is again 10-year inflation swap
rates. So as of right now since Kevin
Worsh went in, we're down here. I don't
know how long this will be, but he was
saying, "Well, the market did it for us.
Real yields are up here. Inflation's
come back down. So we can sit and wait."
Here are the inflation expectations for
the August print around zero.
Dollar positioning. So, this is an
interesting one because when the dollar
weakens, it's usually a very bullish
thing and it's good for gold, it's good
for silver. Uh maybe Jackson Hole will
have an impact on this. Maybe the dollar
yen intervention, but look how big the
crowded positioning is on the dollar.
It's at the highest level in the last
four years.
And the dollar has come down somewhat
this week. Most of it because of this
speculation on the BOJ.
And I just want to highlight for those
of you trading, let's see, end of April,
end of July, end of January. So, this
looks like three months, three months
regardless. It's not pegged, but it sure
seems to be like it's on a
Let's just make sure it doesn't go
anywhere. one podcast for you guys to
pay attention to to kind of figure out
finish out this week. Um, I've heard a
lot of people talk about China, uh, and
they're not in the same plan on AI and
they're looking to just make it free for
the rest of the world. This is a great
interview. Uh, Ezra Klein interviewed
Kevin Rudd, who is the former prime
minister of Australia and an expert in
Xiin Ping. I loved listening to it. I'm
not going to read all this stuff on
there, but for those of you trying to
understand better uh what China is
trying to do and where the balance of
power is in terms of AI and how they're
viewing it, I think this is a really
interesting one. I think Kevin Rudd did
a great job. For those of you who care
about things, the Marxist Lenus lens
combined with the shumper side, it's
really interesting to me. I put this in
myself. So, this is me kind of
extrapolating what I heard, comparing it
to my belief in Joseph Shumper. This is
the reason why I care so much about
Bitcoin. For those of you interested, I
think it's a a great um interview worth
couple things. The cyber stuff is
getting real. Open AAI and hugging face.
You had this hacking. You also had
a Claude hacking as well. Just worth
paying attention to. and the Clarity Act
is sitting here.
It's still below 40% um depending on
which party you listen to. We'll see
what happens. Uh again, I don't think
this matters in the long term uh for
Bitcoin and for crypto. I think it does
matter obviously uh for the
entrepreneurs are involved in the space
and for the short term, we'll see how it
plays out. That's it for this week,
guys. So, final thing, I do believe that
we saw something really important this
week and that based on my history of
dealing with hedge fund unwinds,
those lows matter a lot. Um, and how we
trade over the next six to seven days,
there should be back and forth, but use
that followth through day approach. See
you guys next week.